# Juli A. Brady

Junior Developer

Contact

julibrady@gmail.com 510.207.5031 LinkedIn: /in/julibrady Github: jabrad0 Twitter: @juli\_brady www.julibrady.com



#### **ABOUT ME**

In 2014, I began my journey to become a software engineer and I am now seeking full-time, entry-level opportunities.

I acquired my Civil Engineering license in 2008 from the State of California. I have been an environmental engineer since 2003, specializing in soil and groundwater remediation.

My professional experience has included: managing a small business, managing projects, coordinating with clients, training staff, designing and constructing remediation systems, evaluating data, and writing technical reports.

I bring a professional-level of experience and engineering ability to my new career as a software engineer, in addition to a proven track record of hard work and success.



## **TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE**

## **Software Engineering Fellow**

Hackbright Academy, September 2014 to December 2014 Graduated Hackbright Academy, a highly selective (7.5% acceptance rate) full-time, 10-week, full-stack software engineering immersion program in San Francisco, California.

Curriculum included:

Backend: Python, Flask, SQL, SQLAlchemy Frontend: JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Industry tools: CLI, GIT, Pair Programming, Deployment CS: Data Structures and Algorithms, Best Practices

#### **Technical Online Learning**

Treehouse Academy, January 2015 to Present Udacity, October 2015 to Present Coursera, February 2015



# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Civil/Environmental Engineer**

July 2003 to September 2014

Senior Environmental Engineer

**Streamborn** | Berkeley, CA | October 2013–September 2014

- Prepared proposals and cost estimates for clients.
- Interacted with clients and government regulators daily.
- · Made on-the-spot project decisions in the field.
- Managed simultaneous projects, budgets, and deadlines.

## Junior Environmental Engineer

Iris Environmental | Oakland, CA | April 2011–September 2013

- · Collaborated with teams regarding best project strategies.
- Managed multiple internal staff and professional vendors.
- Developed a sampling program and trained staff on best use.

#### Junior Environmental Engineer

**Streamborn** | Berkeley, CA | November 2006–April 2011

- · Projected and managed project budgets.
- · Designed and constructed remediation systems.
- · Coordinated and planned all components of field work.
- · Managed day-to-day operations of a small business.

#### Staff Engineer

Kennedy/Jenks | Sacramento, CA | July 2003–November 2006

- Conducted field work to investigate contaminated soil and groundwater.
- Produced project investigation reports.
- · Provided QA/QC on large amounts of investigation data.



## **SKILLS**

Python

JavaScript

jQuery

Jinja2

SQL

SQLAlchemy

HTML/CSS

Git

Flask

Ajax



# **PROJECTS**

#### Getgo (5-week solo project)

Designed a web application allowing users to plan an art and wine stroll through Oakland by bike from any location within the city.

Deployed: https://getartandgo.herokuapp.com

Github: jabrad0/Getgo.

Stack: Python, Flask, JavaScript, JQuery, Jinja2, HTML, CSS, Google Maps, JavaScript v3 API, Yelp API

### **Spiritual Corky** (1-week solo project)

Created a twitterbot program that generates a mash-up of quotes from the films "Jesus Christ Superstar" and "Waiting for Guffman" using Markov chains.

Twitter: @Spiritual\_Corky Github: jabrad0/Spiritual\_Corky Stack: Python, Twitter API

## Udacity Front End Nanodegree (6-month online project)

Completed a series of classes to create a portfolio of projects highlighting front end development skills.

Deployed: https://www.julibrady.com Github: https://github.com/jabrad0/portfolio

Stack: Javascript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS, HTML5 Canvas,

Bootstrap, Grunt, GoogleMaps API



## **EDUCATION**

# Masters of Engineering, Biosystems and Agricultural

University of California, Davis Davis, CA | 2001–2003 Published two first author publications in peer-reviewed journals.

#### Bachelor of Engineering, Biosystems and Agricultural

University of Kentucky

Lexington, KY | 1995-2000



## **LICENSURE**

## **Professional Civil Engineer**

California PE License #C72579